hey there thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast if you're a coach
Mentor or trainer this podcast is the
place to learn strategies that work and
get results what I want to talk about is
content creation and coming up with
ideas for Content based on your existing
content this is something that I do
often and now that we have so many great
AI tools that are out there uh my
favorite as of today grock 3 is
incredible we've been using uh deep seek
uh chat GPT all these different AI
algorithms but the way that I use them
is for brainstorming ideas and so one of
my favorite ways is that I will take any
piece of existing content that I have
and I'll have the AI come up with ideas
for me for additional pieces of content
that's related to those and this is how
I actually come up with most of my
content creation ideas in my business is
I have the
AI not just like recycle existing
content that I have but brainstorm new
Concepts around the topics that I'm
doing now one of the best ways to do
this is if you can
have sessions that are Q&A sessions with
real people that you're coaching people
that you're mentoring and so what I love
to do and this is one of the number one
strategies that I recommend to my
clients when they hire me to work
oneon-one with them is are you looking
at your transcripts are you looking
looking at your Q&A sessions are you
taking transcripts of the Q&A sessions
that you spend with clients and using
those to your advantage with AI and so I
want to show you how we've been able to
do that and how to be able to do that
just as an example what I have right
here I have transcripts from actually
three different sessions that I did with
clients and so what I want to do is I
actually want to pull those up with a
and I want to show you the many
different ways that we can use these
transcripts to come up with different
ideas for content and you can do the
same
thing with your transcripts with your uh
AI as well so right here we have the
transcripts and I'm going to open
up uh CAD gbt 40 because that's what
most everybody has right here let's open
up a new chat and I'm going to say
take the
following and generate me 10 ideas for
Instagram reels based on the top
questions asked in these transcripts and
by the way you can take any piece of
content and do this with it you can even
take YouTube
videos and do this I could take any kind
of YouTube video I can
imagine and be able to do this now what
I like to do is take my own content that
I'm doing for example here's a video
that I did about a month ago new updated
sales framework for seven figure coaches
great video if I go into YouTube if I'm
if I'm over here on YouTube
okay I'm going to move the screen over
so you can actually see
it transcript if I go to show transcript
here's the
transcript show transcript is under the
descript rtion now I can copy the
transcript right here and I can open up
another window of chat GPT and I can say
take the following
transcript and generate me 10 ideas for
additional related YouTube videos that
are not the same
topic but would apply to the same Target
customer they need to be related to the
topic of the trans script
below and
connected very closely but different and
then you can just paste the YouTube
content right there and now this is
going to give me some ideas from a video
that I can make on how to do this so
that video is on a sales framework now
we did biggest mistake clients coaches
made to not attract clients and not that
great and what I'm looking for is what
stands out to me what kind of pops out
of the screen as a good idea how to
position yourself as Authority why
coaching offer isn't selling the secret
to getting coaching CS thought lying in
social media how to use email marketing
that's a good one how do use short form
content Psy yeah so let's let's say I'm
going to use this now for my content I'm
going to make a piece of content based
on
this draw some lines map me out an
outline for this training based on this
topic using the
transcripts I gave you
above
okay training
outline What To Expect While email
marketing is a powerful tool why you
need to rely you can't just rely on
social media the psychology behind email
what people buy behind it three core
email sequences lead nurture
sequence uh conversion sequence yep
that's it re-engagement sequence this is
awesome and so what this did was this
gave me an idea now for Content based on
pre-existing content that I already had
from a transcript right there okay let's
go over here reals ideas these are
Instagram reals ideas based on those
transcripts right here secret breath
work hack Le okay so that was actually
something that we were talking about
with one of my clients that was one of
their offers so that is part of the
reason why um it was giving us that why
your social media posts aren't getting
sales and what to do you're posting
every day but nobody's
buying uh content breakdown why organic
posting alone doesn't work to introduce
the power of ads all right so write me
some content around this I can literally
have it write me some content that I can
use around this by organic posting alone
doesn't work reality check posting on
social media every day but you're still
struggling to get clients the algorithm
is on your side no control over reach
audience fatigue what's the solution
strategic lead magnets paid ads that
work think of it this way organic
posting is like fishing with a tiny net
so this is actually really good but I I
don't like the Cadence and the tone of
this
content I don't like the tone of this
make it
more practical down to earth no
emojis
simple simple fifth grade
language
something uh a farmer or a grandma could
understand but still gets the
point across to powerful
CEOs okay so that's another great thing
that I could do why posting daily won't
get you clients lot of people think that
if they just post enough clients will
come here's why most of their followers
never see your post you have no control
over the algorithm likes don't pay the
bills so what works that are hoping to
find the right people have a lead magnet
and then use ads bottom line is posting
every day and hoping for sales into the
reliable strategy yep very true and so
again that's just one example of how I
can come up with content based on my
transcripts and my training that I have
come up with okay now I can do another
thing right here is I could actually
take this and I could use the same
content and I could say take the
transcript this is of the YouTube video
of the
YouTube video alone and split the main
points out into 10 Instagram res
ideas and so what this does is this
gives us different ideas that we could
use to create content and so that's just
a couple of the ways that we can use our
transcripts and exist in content we're
not necessarily just repurposing the
content though there are tools to use
that like Opus clip allows you to take
your own video content and it will
actually clip it down for you into
Instagram reals but this is actually
coming up with ideas for New pieces of
content that you never run out of them
and it helps brainstorm those for you
and so these are ways that I use all the
time whether I'm coaching my coaching
group I'm creating podcasts just like
this one or creating YouTube videos as I
use AI to help me come up with ideas of
what to talk about what to create
content for and you can as well I'd
highly recommend it all right listen if
you want to grow your coaching business
if you want to get more clients I'd love
to work with you in my wealthy coach
Academy program click on one of the
links below and we'll get you some more
info on that talk soon
[Music]
[Applause]